<article>
<preamble>Doyle_2005_Automatic Categorization of Author Gender</preamble>
<titre>Automatic Categorization of Author Gender via N-Gram Analysis </titre>
<auteur>Jonathan Doyle Vlado Kešelj Faculty of Computer Science, Dalhousie University, </auteur>
<abstract>Abstract We present a method for automatic categorization of author gender via n-gram analysis. Using a corpus of British student essays, experi- ments using character-level, word- level, and part-of-speech n-grams are performed. The peak accuracy for all methods is roughly equal, reaching a maximum of 81%. These results are on par with other, established tech- niques, while retaining the simplicity and ease-of-generalization inherent in n-gram techniques. </abstract>
<biblio>References A. Aizawa. 2001. Linguistic techniques to improve the performance of automatic text categoriza- tion. In Proceedings 6th NLP Pac. Rim Symp. NLPRS-01. Shlomo Argamon, Moshe Koppel, Jonathan Fine, and Anat Rachel Shimoni. 2003. Gender, genre, and writing style in formal written texts. Text, 23(3):321–346. W. Cavnar and J. Trenkle. 1994. N-gram-based text categorization. In Proceedings SDAIR-94. Shyamala Doraisamy and Stefan Ruger. 2003. Robust polyphonic music retrieval with n- grams. Journal of Intelligent Information Sys- tems, 21(1):53–70, July. N. Fakotakis E. Stamatatos and G. Kokkinakis. 2000. Automatic text categorization in terms of genre and author. Computational Linguistics, 26(4):471–495. M. Ephratt. 1997. Authorship attribution - the case of lexical innovations. In Proc. ACH-ALLC- 97. Aidan Finn and Nicholas Kushmerick. 2003. Learning to classify documents according to genre. In IJCAI-03 Workshop on Computational Approaches to Style Analysis and Synthesis. Stephen M. Harding, W. Bruce Croft, and C. Weir. 1997. Probabilistic retrieval of ocr degraded text using n-grams. Probabilistic Retrieval of OCR Degraded Text Using N-Grams, 1324:345–359. M. Mahoui I. Witten, Z. Bray and W. Teahan. 1999. Text mining: A new frontier for lossless compression. In Proceedings of the IEEE Data Compression Conference (DCC). Vlado Keselj, Fuchun Peng, Nick Cercone, and Calvin Thomas. 2003. N-gram-based author profiles for authorship attribution. Proceedings of the Conference Pacific Association for Com- putational Linguistics PACLING’03, August. D. Khmelev and W. Teahan. 2003. A repetition based measure for verification of text collections and for text categorization. In SIGIR’2003, Toronto, Canada. Moshe Koppel, Shlomo Argamon, and Anat Rachel Shimoni. 2002. Automatically categorizing writ- ten texts by author gender. Literary and Lin- guistic Computing, 17(4):401–412. Hilary Nesi, Gerard Sharpling, and Lisa Ganobcsik-Williams. 2004. Student papers across the curriculum: Designing and devel- oping a corpus of british student writing. Computers and Composition, 21(4):439–450. R. Rickman and P. Rosin. 1996. Content-based image retrieval using colour n-grams. IEEE Col- loquium on Intelligent Image Databases, pages 15/1–15/6. S. Scott and S. Matwin. 1999. Feature engineering for text classification. In Proceedings ICML-99. E. Stamatatos, N. Fakotakis, and G. Kokkinakis. 2001. Computer-based authorship attribution without lexical measures. Computers and the Humanities, 35:193–214. J. Cleary T. Bell and I. Witten. 1990. Text Com- pression. Prentice Hall. Ying Zhao and Justin Zobel. 2005. Effective and scalable authorship attribution using func- tion words. The 2nd Asia Information Retrieval Symposium. </biblio>
</article>
