<article>
<preamble>Gonzalez_2018_Automated Sentence Boundary Detection in Modern StandardArabic Transcripts using Deep Neural Networks</preamble>
<titre>Available Available online </titre>
<auteur>online at at www.sciencedirect.com </auteur>
<abstract>Abstract Abstract  - Université d’Avignon et des Pays de Vaucluse, 339 chemin des Meinajaries, 84140, Avignon, France du Québec a Montréal, C.P. 8888, succ. Centre-ville, Montréal (Québec) H3C 3P8 Canada c GIGL, École Polytechnique de Montréal, C.P. 6079, succ. Centre-ville, Montréal (Québec) H3C 3A7 Canada b Université  The The increased increased volumes volumes of of Arabic Arabic sources sources of of data data available available on on the the Web Web has has boosted boosted the the development development of of Natural Natural Language Language Processing Processing (NLP) (NLP) tools tools over over different different tasks tasks and and applications. applications. However, However, to to take take advantage advantage from from aa vast vast amount amount of of these these applications, applications, aa prior prior segmentation Abstract segmentation task task call call Sentence Sentence Boundary Boundary Detection Detection (SBD) (SBD) is is needed. needed. In In this this paper paper we we focus focus on on SBD SBD over over Modern Modern Standard Standard Arabic Arabic (MSA) (MSA) by by comparing comparing two two different different approaches approaches based based on on Deep Deep Neural Neural Networks Networks (DNN) (DNN) using using out-of-domain out-of-domain and and in-domain in-domain training training The increased volumes features of Arabic sources of data available on the Web has boosted the development of Natural Language Processing data data with with only only lexical lexical features (represented (represented as as character character embedding) embedding) while while conducting conducting two two scenarios scenarios based based on on aa Convolutional Convolutional (NLP) tools overand different tasks Neural and applications.with However, tomechanism take advantage from a vast amount ofathese applications, a prior Neural Neural Network Network and aa Recurrent Recurrent Neural Network Network with attention attention mechanism architectures. architectures. While While tuning tuning a big big out-of-domain out-of-domain dataset dataset segmentation task call Sentence Boundary Detection (SBD) is needed. In this paper we focus on SBD over Modern Standard Arabic with a smaller in-domain dataset, improves the performance in general. Our evaluations were based on IWSLT with a smaller in-domain dataset, improves the performance in general. Our evaluations were based on IWSLT 2017 2017 TED TED talks talks (MSA) by comparing two different approaches baseddepending on Deep Neural Networks (DNN)MSA usingcarries out-of-domain and in-domaingiven training transcripts and showed similarities and differences of the SBD method. certain complications transcripts and showed similarities and differences depending of the SBD method. MSA carries certain complications given its its data with only lexical features (represented as character embedding) while conducting two scenarios based on the a Convolutional rich rich and and complex complex morphology. morphology. However, However, using using only only lexical lexical features features for for Arabic Arabic SBD SBD is is an an acceptable acceptable option option when when the source source audio audio Neural Network and a Recurrent Neural Network with attention mechanism architectures. While tuning a big out-of-domain dataset signal signal is is not not available available and and aa certain certain level level of of language language independence independence needs needs to to be be reached. reached. with a smaller in-domain dataset, improves the performance in general. Our evaluations were based on IWSLT 2017 TED talks Sentence Boundary Detection; Transcription; Modern Neural Networks Keywords: transcripts showed similarities andSpeech-to-Text; differences of the SBDStandard method.Arabic; MSADeep carries certain complications given its © 2018 Theand Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V. depending Keywords: Sentence Boundary Detection; Speech-to-Text; Transcription; Modern Standard Arabic; Deep Neural Networks rich and complex morphology. However, using only lexical features for Arabic SBD is an acceptable option when the source audio This is an open access article under the CC BY-NC-ND license (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/) signal is not under available and a certain level of language independence to be reached. Peer-review responsibility of the scientific committee of the 4thneeds International Conference on Arabic Computational Linguistics. Keywords: Sentence Boundary Detection; Speech-to-Text; Transcription; Modern Standard Arabic; Deep Neural Networks  1. </abstract>
<introduction>1. Introduction Introduction Arabic Arabic language language is is known known to to be be challenging challenging given given its its complex complex linguistic linguistic structure structure [3] [3] and and dialect dialect variations variations [14]. [14]. However, the development of Arabic Natural Language Processing (NLP) tools has increased these last However, the development of Arabic Natural Language Processing (NLP) tools has increased these last years, years, creating creating 1. Introduction aa large large set set of of state-of-the-art state-of-the-art applications applications including including POS POS taggers, taggers, syntactic syntactic parsers, parsers, information information retrieval, retrieval, machine machine translation, automatic speech recognition and synthesis systems [9, 17]. Some NLP libraries and like translation, automatic speech and given synthesis systems linguistic [9, 17]. Some NLP [3] libraries and tools tools like Python Python Arabic language is known to recognition be challenging its complex structure and dialect variations [14]. However, the development of Arabic Natural Language Processing (NLP) tools has increased these last years, creating a ∗large set of state-of-the-art applications author. Tel.: +33 04 90 84 35 68. including POS taggers, syntactic parsers, information retrieval, machine ∗ Corresponding Corresponding author. Tel.: +33 04 90 84 35 68. translation, automatic speech recognition and synthesis systems [9, 17]. Some NLP libraries and tools like Python E-mail address: carlos-emiliano.gonzalez-gallardo@alumni.univ-avignon.fr E-mail address: carlos-emiliano.gonzalez-gallardo@alumni.univ-avignon.fr  c 2018 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V. 1877-0509  c 2018 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V. 1877-0509  ∗ is an open 1877-0509 © 2018 Thearticle Authors. Published by35Elsevier B.V. This access under the CC84 BY-NC-ND license (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/) author. Tel.: +33 04 90 68. ThisCorresponding is an open access article under the CC BY-NC-ND license (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/) This is an open access article under CC BY-NC-ND (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/) Peer-review under responsibility of thethe scientific committeelicense of the 4th International Conference on Arabic Computational Linguistics. E-mail address: carlos-emiliano.gonzalez-gallardo@alumni.univ-avignon.fr Peer-review under responsibility of the scientific committee of theof4th International Conference on ArabiconComputational Linguistics.Linguistics. Peer-review under responsibility of the scientific committee the 4th International Conference Arabic Computational 10.1016/j.procs.2018.10.485 c 2018 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V. 1877-0509  This is an open access article under the CC BY-NC-ND license (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/) Peer-review under responsibility of the scientific committee of the 4th International Conference on Arabic Computational Linguistics. </introduction>
<corp>340	 2  Carlos-Emiliano González-Gallardo et al. / Procedia Computer Science 142 (2018) 339–346 C.E. González-Gallardo et al. / Procedia Computer Science 00 (2018) 000–000  NLTK1 , OpenNLP2 [5], UIMA3 [10], LIMA4 and NooJ5 [26], which were originally created for non Arabic texts now include Arabic extensions. By contrast, other libraries have been developed exclusively for Arabic. Althobaiti et al. developed AraNLP [2], which is focused on Arabic preprocessing. This library contains some tools covering tokenization, stemming, POS tagging, sentence detection, word segmentation, normalization and punctuation/diacritic deletion. MADAMIRA6 , developed by Pasha et al., is an toolkit which combines two previous Arabic NLP systems: MADA[13] and AMIRA[7]. It provides the following NLP tools for Modern Standard Arabic (MSA) and the Egyptian dialect: lemmatization, diacritization, glossing, POS tagging, morphological analysis, morphological disambiguation, stemming, tokenization, base phrase chunking, name entity recognition and word-level disambiguation [23]. The Software Architecture For Arabic language pRocessing (SAFAR) [27] is a framework developed by Souteh et al. that aims to gather developed Arabic NLP tools within a single homogeneous architecture and create new ones if necessary. Implemented tools within SAFAR include morphological analyzers, stemmers, syntactic parsers, normalizers, tokenizers, sentence splitters, transliteration tools and question answering applications. Works have also been made regarding unstructured and noisy Arabic texts, found in social media datasets like microblogs and tweets. Added to the common difficulties of working with structured Arabic texts, Arabic tweets carry other problems like high degree of ambiguity, spelling mistakes, etc. Mallek et al. [20] implemented a phrase-based statistical machine translation system from MSA tweets into English. They conclude that a preprocessing step for this kind of noisy texts is very useful to improve the translation results. El-Masri et al. [8] presented a sentiment analysis tool over Arabic tweets using a Naive Bayes learning approach. Their model detects the polarity of a group of tweet classifying it in four possible classes: positive, negative, both and neutral. Access to Internet multimedia platforms nowadays available like Youtube7 , TED8 and Dailymotion9 opens a new universe for Arabic NLP tools. Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR) systems can be used to transcribe multimedia content ASR aims to transform spoken data into a written representation, thus enabling natural human-machine interaction with further NLP tasks [31]. Performance of ASR systems for MSA has improve in the last years given the amount of data available for training and testing this systems. Tomashenko et al. [28] trained a Deep Neural Network (DNN) with Gaussian Mixture Models derived features and time-delay neural networks for acoustic models over 1128 hours of MSA broadcast speech and 110 million words, reporting a WER of 23%. Menacer et al. [21] developed an ASR system for MSA based on the Kaldi toolkit10 [25], where recognition is achieved using a DNN Hidden Markov model over 63 hours of spoken transcribed data and 1000 million words from the Arabic Gigaword Corpus. They reported a result of 14.42% in terms of WER. Despite the good performance of modern ASR systems, transcripts do not carry syntactic information as sentence boundaries, which is a major problem for further NLP tasks like POS tagging, automatic text summarization [29], machine translation and sentiment analysis among others. In this paper we address the Sentence Boundary Detection (SBD) task over MSA transcripts to automatically predict or restore the boundaries over transcripts. The rest of this article is organized as follows. In Section 2 we present an overview of related work concerning SBD. The experimental setup is introduced in Section 3. Experiments and results are addressed in Section 4. In Section 5 </corp>
<conclusion></conclusion>
<references>References [1] Alotaiby, F., Foda, S., Alkharashi, I., 2010. Clitics in arabic language: a statistical study, in: 24th Pacific Asia Conference on Language, Information and Computation. [2] Althobaiti, M., Kruschwitz, U., Poesio, M., 2014. Aranlp: A java-based library for the processing of arabic text, in: LREC. [3] Attia, M., Somers, H., 2008. Handling Arabic morphological and syntactic ambiguity within the LFG framework with a view to machine translation. volume 279. University of Manchester Manchester. [4] Bahdanau, D., Cho, K., Bengio, Y., 2014. Neural machine translation by jointly learning to align and translate. CoRR abs/1409.0473. [5] Baldridge, J., 2005. The OpenNLP project. http://opennlp.apache.org/. [6] Bojanowski, P., Grave, E., Joulin, A., Mikolov, T., 2016. Enriching word vectors with subword information. preprint arXiv:1607.04606 . [7] Diab, M., 2009. Second generation amira tools for arabic processing: Fast and robust tokenization, pos tagging, and base phrase chunking, in: 2nd International Conference on Arabic Language Resources and Tools. [8] El-Masri, M., Altrabsheh, N., Mansour, H., Ramsay, A., 2017. A web-based tool for arabic sentiment analysis. Procedia Computer Science 117, 38–45. [9] Farghaly, A., Shaalan, K., 2009. Arabic natural language processing: Challenges and solutions. ACM Transactions on Asian Language Information Processing (TALIP) 8, 14. [10] Ferrucci, D., Lally, A., 2004. UIMA: An Architectural Approach to Unstructured Information Processing in the Corporate Research Environment. Natural Language Engineering 10, 327–348. doi:10.1017/S1351324904003523. [11] González-Gallardo, C.E., Torres-Moreno, J.M., 2018. Sentence Boundary Detection for French with Subword-Level Information Vectors and Convolutional Neural Networks. preprint arXiv:1802.04559 . [12] Gotoh, Y., Renals, S., 2000. Sentence boundary detection in broadcast speech transcripts, in: ASR2000-Automatic Speech Recognition: Challenges for the new Millenium ISCA Tutorial and Research Workshop (ITRW). [13] Habash, N., Rambow, O., Roth, R., 2009. Mada+ tokan: A toolkit for arabic tokenization, diacritization, morphological disambiguation, pos tagging, stemming and lemmatization, in: 2nd International Conference on Arabic language resources and tools (MEDAR), Cairo, Egypt, p. 62. [14] Habash, N.Y., 2010. Introduction to arabic natural language processing. Synthesis Lectures on Human Language Technologies 3, 1–187. [15] Hadrich, L.B., Baccour, L., Mourad, G., 2005. Star: un système de segmentation de textes arabes basé sur lanalyse contextuelle des signes de ponctuations et de certaines particules, in: TALN’05. [16] Hochreiter, S., Schmidhuber, J., 1997. Long short-term memory. Neural Computation 9, 1735–1780. [17] Jaafar, Y., Bouzoubaa, K., 2018. A survey and comparative study of arabic nlp architectures, in: Intelligent Natural Language Processing: Trends and Applications. Springer, pp. 585–610. [18] Linhares Pontes, E., Huet, S., Torres-Moreno, J.M., Linhares, A.C., 2018. Cross-language text summarization using sentence and multisentence compression, in: Silberztein, M., Atigui, F., Kornyshova, E., Métais, E., Meziane, F. (Eds.), Natural Language Processing and Information Systems, Springer International Publishing, Cham. pp. 467–479. [19] Liu, Y., Chawla, N.V., Harper, M.P., Shriberg, E., Stolcke, A., 2006. A study in machine learning from imbalanced data for sentence boundary detection in speech. Computer Speech & Language 20, 468–494. [20] Mallek, F., Le, N.T., Sadat, F., 2018. Automatic machine translation for arabic tweets, in: Intelligent Natural Language Processing: Trends and Applications. Springer, pp. 101–119. [21] Menacer, M.A., Mella, O., Fohr, D., Jouvet, D., Langlois, D., Smaili, K., 2017. An enhanced automatic speech recognition system for arabic, in: Third Arabic Natural Language Processing Workshop, pp. 157–165. [22] Mikolov, T., Chen, K., Corrado, G., Dean, J., 2013. Efficient estimation of word representations in vector space. preprint arXiv:1301.3781 . [23] Pasha, A., Al-Badrashiny, M., Diab, M.T., El Kholy, A., Eskander, R., Habash, N., Pooleery, M., Rambow, O., Roth, R., 2014. Madamira: A fast, comprehensive tool for morphological analysis and disambiguation of arabic., in: LREC, pp. 1094–1101. [24] Pennington, J., Socher, R., Manning, C., 2014. Glove: Global vectors for word representation, in: Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), pp. 1532–1543. [25] Povey, D., Ghoshal, A., Boulianne, G., Burget, L., Glembek, O., Goel, N., Hannemann, M., Motlicek, P., Qian, Y., Schwarz, P., et al., 2011. The Kaldi speech recognition toolkit, in: IEEE 2011 Workshop on Automatic Speech Recognition and Understanding, IEEE Signal Processing Society. [26] Silberztein, M., 2005. Nooj: a linguistic annotation system for corpus processing, in: HLT/EMNLP on Interactive Demonstrations, Association for Computational Linguistics. pp. 10–11. [27] Souteh, Y., Bouzoubaa, K., 2011. Safar platform and its morphological layer, in: Eleventh Conference on Language Engineering ESOLEC, pp. 14–15. [28] Tomashenko, N., Vythelingum, K., Rousseau, A., Estève, Y., 2016. Lium asr systems for the 2016 multi-genre broadcast arabic challenge, in: Spoken Language Technology Workshop (SLT), 2016, IEEE. pp. 285–291. [29] Torres-Moreno, J.M., 2014. Automatic Text Summarization. Wiley and Sons. [30] Tran, N.T., Luong, V.T., Nguyen, N.L.T., Nghiem, M.Q., 2016. Effective attention-based neural architectures for sentence compression with bidirectional long short-term memory, in: Seventh Symposium on Information and Communication Technology, ACM, New York, NY, USA. pp. 123–130. URL: http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/3011077.3011111, doi:10.1145/3011077.3011111. [31] Yu, D., Deng, L., 2016. Automatic Speech Recognition. Springer. [32] Zribi, I., Kammoun, I., Ellouze, M., Belguith, L., Blache, P., 2016. Sentence boundary detection for transcribed tunisian arabic, in: 13th Conference on Natural Language Processing (KONVENS 2016), pp. 323–331. </references>
</article>
