<article>
<preamble>Alexandrov_2015_A Modified Tripartite Model for Document Representation in Internet Sociology</preamble>
<titre>A Modified Tripartite Model for Document Representation in Internet Sociology </titre>
<auteur>Mikhail Alexandrov1,2 , Vera Danilova1,2(B) , and Xavier Blanco1 </auteur>
<abstract>Abstract. Seven years ago Peter Mika (Yahoo! Research) proposed a tripartite model of actors, concepts and instances for document representation in the study of social networks. We propose a modified model, where instead of document authors we consider textual mentions of persons and institutions as actors. This representation proves to be more appropriate for the solution of a range of Internet Sociology tasks. In the paper we describe experiments with the modified model and provide some background on the tools that can be used to build it. The model is tested on the experimental corpora of Russian news (educational domain). The research reflects the pilot study findings. Keywords: Tripartite model · Document representation Social networks analysis · Internet sociology  1  ·  Ontology  ·  </abstract>
<introduction>Introduction  The automatic detection of document and corpus topic is one of the most popular tasks within the natural language processing. The traditional model, where each document is represented by a vector describing the distribution of keywords in a document or corpus, works quite well. On the basis of this representation, it becomes possible to group similar documents and reveal the corpus structure, as well as to group keywords and build topic vocabularies [6,11]. Considering each document as an ontology instance and a set of keywords as a concept, we obtain a two-layer ontology model. The appearance of social networks allowed the researchers to bring in the social aspect, thus creating a tripartite model of ontology for Social Networks Analysis containing document authors (actors), document content (instances), and tags (concepts) [13]. Three-layer model is a tool for studying the emergence and dynamics of communities on the basis of user-generated content. Author proﬁling gave an opportunity to analyze the Under partial support of the Catholic University of San Pablo (grant FINCyTPERU). c Springer International Publishing Switzerland 2015  Q. Chen et al. (Eds.): DEXA 2015, Part II, LNCS 9262, pp. 323–330, 2015. DOI: 10.1007/978-3-319-22852-5 27 </introduction>
<corp>324  M. Alexandrov et al.  attitude of diﬀerent user categories towards particular events and topics. However, it is not only the author’s personality that matters for solving Internet Sociology tasks, but also the awareness of the connection between the text mentions of personalities and organizations and concepts and instances within text. This knowledge is important, when dealing with traditional mass media - epublications created by analysts and journalists. In this case, the Actor in the Actor-Concept-Instance triple is a Named Entity (NE) mention (person and organization names), the Concept is an automatically generated topic description, not user-generated tags, and the Instance is a set of phrases with a high level of speciﬁcity that frequently denote events (olympiad, demonstration, etc.). The present paper considers the use of this modiﬁed tripartite model of ontologies for the purposes of Internet Sociology studies. The rest of the article is organized as follows. Section 2 provides a description of the three-layer model. Section 3 presents the experiments on real-world data that include model construction, opinion mining and clustering. Section 4 concludes the paper. This paper outlines our pilot-study experiments performed on the basis of Russian newspaper articles. The listed examples are translated into English.  2  Multipartite Models  2.1  Tripartite Model  The tripartite model uses three layers of descriptors (keywords) for document representation as follows. The ﬁrst layer is formed from a list of actors or person and organization names that are mentioned in a document; the second layer is a list of concepts that characterize the domain a given document belongs to; the third layer is represented by the instances or document-speciﬁc collocations. Each element of each list contains a set of tokens, which number varies from 1 to 5. As for a single document, the tripartite model can be created for a corpus of documents. The corpus representation is a list of actors, concepts and instances that are mentioned throughout a corpus. Table 1 presents an excerpt from a model for a corpus of 250 documents related to the educational domain. Here, the NE “Dr. Livanov” is a mention of the Russian Minister of Education </corp>
<conclusion></conclusion>
<references>References 1. Alexandrov, M.: Development of general methodology for analysis of public opinion of Internet-community and its application to given topics (authority, economy, corruption, etc.) on the basis of Data/Text Mining tools. Report on State project 84, RPANEPA [rus] (2013) 2. Alexandrov, M., Beresneva, D., Makarov, A.: Dynamic vocabularies as a tool for studying social processes. In: Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on Intelligent Information and Engineering Systems, ITHEA Publishing, vol. 27, pp. 88–92 (2014) 3. Alexandrov, M., Danilova, V., Koshulko, A., Tejada, J.: Models for opinion classification of blogs taken from Peruvian Facebook. In: Proceedings of the 4th International Conference on Inductive Modeling (ICIM-2013), Kyiv, Ukraine Publishing House ITRC-NASU (Ukraine) & Czech Technical University pp. 241–246 (2013) 4. Alexandrov, M., Gelbukh, A., Rosso, P.: An approach to clustering abstracts. In: Montoyo, A., Muñoz, R., Métais, E. (eds.) NLDB 2005. LNCS, vol. 3513, pp. 275–285. Springer, Heidelberg (2005) 5. Alexandrov, M., Gelbukh, A., Makagonov, P.: Evaluation of thematic structure of multidisciplinary documents and document flows. In: Proceedings of the 11th International DEXA Workshop (Database and Expert System Applications), pp. 125–129 (2000) 6. Baeza-Yates, R., Ribero-Neto, B.: Modern Information Retrieval. Addison Wesley, Boston (1999) 7. Bishop, C.: Pattern Recognition and Machine Learning. Springer, Berkeley (2006) 8. Danilova, V., Alexandrov, M., Blanco, X.: A survey of multilingual event extraction from text. In: Métais, E., Roche, M., Teisseire, M. (eds.) NLDB 2014. LNCS, vol. 8455, pp. 85–88. Springer, Heidelberg (2014) 9. Danilova V., Popova S.: Socio-political event extraction using a rule-based approach. In: Meersman, R., Panetto, H., Mishra, A., Valencia-Garcia, R., Soares, A.L., Ciuciu, I., Ferri, F., Weichhart, G., Moser, T., Bezzi, M., Chan, H. (eds.) Proceedings of the 13th International Conference on Ontologies, DataBases and Applications of Semantics (ODBASE’2014), vol 8842, pp. 537–546, Springer (2014) 10. Gelbukh, A., Sidorov, G., Guzman-Arenas, A.: Use of a weighted topic hierarchy for document classification. In: Matoušek, V., et al. (eds.) TSD 1999. LNCS (LNAI), vol. 1692, pp. 133–138. Springer, Heidelberg (1999) 11. Manning, C., Raghavan, P., Schutze, H.: Introduction to Information Retrieval. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge (2008) 12. Eissen, S.M., Stein, B.: Analysis of clustering algorithms for web-based search. In: Karagiannis, D., Reimer, U. (eds.) PAKM 2002. LNCS (LNAI), vol. 2569, pp. 168–178. Springer, Heidelberg (2002) 13. Mika, P.: Ontologies are us: a unified model of social networks and semantics. J. Web Semant. Sci. Serv. Agents World Wide Web 5(1), 5–15 (2007) 14. Stein, B., Niggemann, O.: On the nature of structure and its identification. In: Widmayer, P., Neyer, G., Eidenbenz, S. (eds.) WG 1999. LNCS, vol. 1665, p. 122. Springer, Heidelberg (1999) </references>
</article>
