<article>
<preamble>Torres-Moreno_2012_Artex is another text summarizer</preamble>
<titre>Artex is AnotheR TEXt summarizer Juan-Manuel Torres-Moreno1,2 </titre>
<auteur>1 </auteur>
<abstract>Abstract This paper describes Artex, another algorithm for Automatic Text Summarization. In order to rank sentences, a simple inner product is calculated between each sentence, a document vector (text topic) and a lexical vector (vocabulary used by a sentence). Summaries are then generated by assembling the highest ranked sentences. No ruled-based linguistic post-processing is necessary in order to obtain summaries. Tests over several datasets (coming from Document Understanding Conferences (DUC), Text Analysis Conference (TAC), evaluation campaigns, etc.) in French, English and Spanish have shown that Artex summarizer achieves interesting results. </abstract>
<biblio>References [1] Iria da Cunha, Silvia Fernández, Patricia Velázquez-Morales, Jorge Vivaldi, Eric SanJuan, and Juan Manuel Torres-Moreno. A new hybrid summarizer based on vector space model, statistical physics and linguistics. In Proceedings of the 6th Mexican International Conference on Advances in Artificial Intelligence (MICAI’07), pages 872–882, Aguascalientes, Mexico, 2007. Springer-Verlag. [2] Harold Daumé III. Practical structured learning techniques for natural language processing. PhD thesis, Los Angeles, CA, 2006. [3] H. P. Edmundson. New Methods in Automatic Extraction. Journal of the Association for Computing Machinery, 16(2):264–285, 1969. [4] B. Favre, F. Béchet, P. Bellot, F. Boudin, M. El-Bèze, L. Gillard, G. Lapalme, and J-M. TorresMoreno. The LIA-Thales summarization system at DUC-2006. In Proceedings of the Document Understanding Conference (DUC’06), Brooklyn, New York, United States, 2006. http://duc.nist.gov. [5] Silvia Fernández, Eric SanJuan, and Juan-Manuel Torres-Moreno. Textual Energy of Associative Memories: performants applications of Enertex algorithm in text summarization and topic segmentation. In Proceedings of the Mexican International Conference on Artificial Intelligence (MICAI’07), pages 861–871, Aguascalientes, Mexico, 2007. Springer-Verlag. [6] J. Kupiec, J. Pedersen, and F. Chen. A trainable document summarizer. In Proceedings of the 18th Conference ACM Special Interest Group on Information Retrieval (SIGIR’95), pages 68–73, Seattle, WA, United States, 1995. ACM Press, New York. [7] Chin-Yew Lin. ROUGE: A Package for Automatic Evaluation of Summaries. In Marie-Francine Moens and Stan Szpakowicz, editors, Proceedings of the Workshop Text Summarization Branches Out (ACL’04), pages 74–81, Barcelone, Spain, july 2004. ACL. [8] Annie Louis and Ani Nenkova. Automatic Summary Evaluation without Human Models. In First Text Analysis Conference (TAC’08), Gaithersburg, MD, United States, 17-19 November 2008. [9] H.P. Luhn. The Automatic Creation of Literature Abstracts. IBM Journal of Research and Development, 2(2):159–165, 1958. [10] I. Mani and M. Mayburi. Advances in Automatic Text Summarization. MIT Press, Cambridge, 1999. [11] Eric SanJuan, Patrice Bellot, Véronique Moriceau, and Xavier Tannier. Overview of the INEX 2010 Question Answering Track (QA@INEX). In Shlomo Geva, Jaap Kamps, Ralf Schenkel, and Andrew Trotman, editors, Comparative Evaluation of Focused Retrieval, volume 6932 of Lecture Notes in Computer Science, pages 269–281. Springer Berlin / Heidelberg, 2011.  [12] Simone Teufel and Marc Moens. Sentence extraction as a classification task. In I. Mani and M. Maybury, editors, Proceedings of the ACL/EACL’97 Workshop on Intelligent Scalable Text Summarization, Madrid, Spain, 11 July 1997. [13] J.-M. Torres-Moreno, Horacio Saggion, I. da Cunha, P. Velazquez-Morales, and E. SanJuan. Evaluation automatique de résumés avec et sans réferences. In Proceedings de la conference Traitement Automatique des Langagues Naturelles (TALN’10), Montréal, QC, Canada, 19-23 July 2010. ATALA. [14] J.-M. Torres-Moreno, P.-L. St-Onge, M. Gagnon, M. El-Bèze, and P. Bellot. Automatic Summarization System coupled with a Question-Answering System (QAAS). CoRR, abs/0905.2990, 2009. [15] Juan-Manuel Torres-Moreno. Résumé automatique de documents: une approche statistique. Hermès-Lavoisier, Paris, 2011. [16] Juan-Manuel Torres-Moreno. Beyond Stemming and Lemmatization: Ultra-stemming to Improve Automatic Text Summarization. CoRR, arXiv:1209.3126 [cs.IR], 2012. [17] Juan-Manuel Torres-Moreno, Horacio Saggion, Iria da Cunha, and Eric SanJuan. Summary Evaluation With and Without References. Polibits: Research journal on Computer science and computer engineering with applications, 42:13–19, 2010. [18] Juan-Manuel Torres-Moreno, Patricia Velázquez-Morales, and Jean-Guy Meunier. Cortex : un algorithme pour la condensation automatique des textes. In Proceedings of the Conference de l’Association pour la Recherche Cognitive, volume 2, pages 365–366, Lyon, France, 2001.  </biblio>
</article>
