<article>
<preamble>Levner_2007_Fuzzifying clustering algorithms The case study of MajorClust</preamble>
<titre>Fuzzifying clustering algorithms: The case study of MajorClust </titre>
<auteur>Eugene Levner1 , David Pinto(2,3) </auteur>
<abstract>Abstract. Among various document clustering algorithms that have been proposed so far, the most useful are those that automatically re- veal the number of clusters and assign each target document to exactly one cluster. However, in many real situations, there not exists an exact boundary between different clusters. In this work, we introduce a fuzzy version of the MajorClust algorithm. The proposed clustering method assigns documents to more than one category by taking into account a membership function for both, edges and nodes of the corresponding underlying graph. Thus, the clustering problem is formulated in terms of weighted fuzzy graphs. The fuzzy approach permits to decrease some negative effects which appear in clustering of large-sized corpora with noisy data. </abstract>
<biblio>References 1. MacKay, D.J.: Information Theory, Inference and Learning Algorithms. Cambridge University Press (2003) 2. Mirkin, B.: Mathematical Classification and Clustering. Springer (1996) 3. MacQueen, J.B.: Some methods for classification and analysis of multivariate observations. In: Proc. of 5-th Berkeley Symposium on Mathematical Statistics and Probability, Berkeley, University of California Press (1967) 281–297 4. Kernighan, B., Lin, S.: An efficient heuristic procedure for partitioning graphs. Bell Systems Technical Journal 49(2) (1970) 291–308 5. Stein, B., Nigemman, O.: On the nature of structure and its identification. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, Springer 1665 (1999) 122–134 6. Dunn, J.C.: A fuzzy relative of the isodata process and its use in detecting compact well-separated clusters. Journal of Cybernetics 3 (1973) 32–57 7. Bezdek, J.C.: Pattern Recognition with Fuzzy Objective Function Algoritms. Plenum Press, New York (1981) 8. Stein, B., Busch, M.: Density-based cluster algorithms in low-dimensional and high-dimensional applications. In: Proc. of Second International Workshop on Text-Based Information Retrieval, TIR05. (2005) 45–56 9. Stein, B., Meyer, S.: Automatic document categorization. In: KI 2003: Advances in Artificial Intelligence. (2003) 254–266 10. Alexandrov, M., Gelbukh, A., Rosso, P.: An approach to clustering abstracts. In: Proc. of NLDB 2005 Conference, LNCS 3513, Springer, Verlag (2005) 275–285 11. Pinto, D., Rosso, P.: On the relative hardness of clustering corpora. In: Proc. of TSD 2007 Conference, LNCS, Springer, Verlag (2007) To appear. 12. Neville, J., Adler, M., Jensen, D.: Clustering relational data using attribute and link information. In: Proc. of the Text Mining and Link Analysis Workshop, IJ- CAI03. (2003) 13. Levner, E., Alcaide, D., Sicilia, J.: Text classification using the fuzzy borda method and semantic grades. In: Proc. of WILF-2007 (CLIP-2007). Volume 4578 of LNAI., LNAI, Springer, Verlag (2007) 422–429 14. Levner, E., Alcaide, D.: Environmental risk ranking: Theory and applications for emergency planning. Scientific Israel - Technological Advantages 8(1-2) (2006) 11–21 15. Koopmans, T., Beckman, M.: Assignment problems and the location of economic activities. Econometrica 25 (1957) 53–76 16. Singh, S., Sharma, R.: A review of different approaches to the facility layout problem. International Journal of Advanced Manufacutring Technology 30(5–6) (2006) 426–433 http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00170-005-0087-9. 17. Klawonn, F., Höpnner, F.: What is fuzzy about fuzzy clustering-understanding and improving the concept of the fuzzifier. Advances in Intelligent Data Analysis V. (2003) 254–264 18. Mamdani, E.H.: Application of fuzzy logic to approximate reasoning using linguis- tic synthesis. In: Proc. of the sixth international symposium on Multiple-valued logic. (1976) 196–202 19. Zimmermann, H.: Fuzzy Sets, Decision Making and Expert Systems. Kluwer Academic Publishers, Boston (1987) </biblio>
</article>
