<article>
<preamble>Gonzalez_2018_Automated Sentence Boundary Detection in Modern StandardArabic Transcripts using Deep Neural Networks</preamble>
<titre>Available Available online </titre>
<auteur>online at at www.sciencedirect.com </auteur>
<abstract>Abstract Abstract </abstract>
<biblio>References [1] Alotaiby, F., Foda, S., Alkharashi, I., 2010. Clitics in arabic language: a statistical study, in: 24th Pacific Asia Conference on Language, Information and Computation. [2] Althobaiti, M., Kruschwitz, U., Poesio, M., 2014. Aranlp: A java-based library for the processing of arabic text, in: LREC. [3] Attia, M., Somers, H., 2008. Handling Arabic morphological and syntactic ambiguity within the LFG framework with a view to machine translation. volume 279. University of Manchester Manchester. [4] Bahdanau, D., Cho, K., Bengio, Y., 2014. Neural machine translation by jointly learning to align and translate. CoRR abs/1409.0473. [5] Baldridge, J., 2005. The OpenNLP project. http://opennlp.apache.org/. [6] Bojanowski, P., Grave, E., Joulin, A., Mikolov, T., 2016. Enriching word vectors with subword information. preprint arXiv:1607.04606 . [7] Diab, M., 2009. Second generation amira tools for arabic processing: Fast and robust tokenization, pos tagging, and base phrase chunking, in: 2nd International Conference on Arabic Language Resources and Tools. [8] El-Masri, M., Altrabsheh, N., Mansour, H., Ramsay, A., 2017. A web-based tool for arabic sentiment analysis. Procedia Computer Science 117, 38–45. [9] Farghaly, A., Shaalan, K., 2009. Arabic natural language processing: Challenges and solutions. ACM Transactions on Asian Language Information Processing (TALIP) 8, 14. [10] Ferrucci, D., Lally, A., 2004. UIMA: An Architectural Approach to Unstructured Information Processing in the Corporate Research Environment. Natural Language Engineering 10, 327–348. doi:10.1017/S1351324904003523. [11] González-Gallardo, C.E., Torres-Moreno, J.M., 2018. Sentence Boundary Detection for French with Subword-Level Information Vectors and Convolutional Neural Networks. preprint arXiv:1802.04559 . [12] Gotoh, Y., Renals, S., 2000. Sentence boundary detection in broadcast speech transcripts, in: ASR2000-Automatic Speech Recognition: Challenges for the new Millenium ISCA Tutorial and Research Workshop (ITRW). [13] Habash, N., Rambow, O., Roth, R., 2009. Mada+ tokan: A toolkit for arabic tokenization, diacritization, morphological disambiguation, pos tagging, stemming and lemmatization, in: 2nd International Conference on Arabic language resources and tools (MEDAR), Cairo, Egypt, p. 62. [14] Habash, N.Y., 2010. Introduction to arabic natural language processing. Synthesis Lectures on Human Language Technologies 3, 1–187. [15] Hadrich, L.B., Baccour, L., Mourad, G., 2005. Star: un système de segmentation de textes arabes basé sur lanalyse contextuelle des signes de ponctuations et de certaines particules, in: TALN’05. [16] Hochreiter, S., Schmidhuber, J., 1997. Long short-term memory. Neural Computation 9, 1735–1780. [17] Jaafar, Y., Bouzoubaa, K., 2018. A survey and comparative study of arabic nlp architectures, in: Intelligent Natural Language Processing: Trends and Applications. Springer, pp. 585–610. [18] Linhares Pontes, E., Huet, S., Torres-Moreno, J.M., Linhares, A.C., 2018. Cross-language text summarization using sentence and multisentence compression, in: Silberztein, M., Atigui, F., Kornyshova, E., Métais, E., Meziane, F. (Eds.), Natural Language Processing and Information Systems, Springer International Publishing, Cham. pp. 467–479. [19] Liu, Y., Chawla, N.V., Harper, M.P., Shriberg, E., Stolcke, A., 2006. A study in machine learning from imbalanced data for sentence boundary detection in speech. Computer Speech & Language 20, 468–494. [20] Mallek, F., Le, N.T., Sadat, F., 2018. Automatic machine translation for arabic tweets, in: Intelligent Natural Language Processing: Trends and Applications. Springer, pp. 101–119. [21] Menacer, M.A., Mella, O., Fohr, D., Jouvet, D., Langlois, D., Smaili, K., 2017. An enhanced automatic speech recognition system for arabic, in: Third Arabic Natural Language Processing Workshop, pp. 157–165. [22] Mikolov, T., Chen, K., Corrado, G., Dean, J., 2013. Efficient estimation of word representations in vector space. preprint arXiv:1301.3781 . [23] Pasha, A., Al-Badrashiny, M., Diab, M.T., El Kholy, A., Eskander, R., Habash, N., Pooleery, M., Rambow, O., Roth, R., 2014. Madamira: A fast, comprehensive tool for morphological analysis and disambiguation of arabic., in: LREC, pp. 1094–1101. [24] Pennington, J., Socher, R., Manning, C., 2014. Glove: Global vectors for word representation, in: Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), pp. 1532–1543. [25] Povey, D., Ghoshal, A., Boulianne, G., Burget, L., Glembek, O., Goel, N., Hannemann, M., Motlicek, P., Qian, Y., Schwarz, P., et al., 2011. The Kaldi speech recognition toolkit, in: IEEE 2011 Workshop on Automatic Speech Recognition and Understanding, IEEE Signal Processing Society. [26] Silberztein, M., 2005. Nooj: a linguistic annotation system for corpus processing, in: HLT/EMNLP on Interactive Demonstrations, Association for Computational Linguistics. pp. 10–11. [27] Souteh, Y., Bouzoubaa, K., 2011. Safar platform and its morphological layer, in: Eleventh Conference on Language Engineering ESOLEC, pp. 14–15. [28] Tomashenko, N., Vythelingum, K., Rousseau, A., Estève, Y., 2016. Lium asr systems for the 2016 multi-genre broadcast arabic challenge, in: Spoken Language Technology Workshop (SLT), 2016, IEEE. pp. 285–291. [29] Torres-Moreno, J.M., 2014. Automatic Text Summarization. Wiley and Sons. [30] Tran, N.T., Luong, V.T., Nguyen, N.L.T., Nghiem, M.Q., 2016. Effective attention-based neural architectures for sentence compression with bidirectional long short-term memory, in: Seventh Symposium on Information and Communication Technology, ACM, New York, NY, USA. pp. 123–130. URL: http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/3011077.3011111, doi:10.1145/3011077.3011111. [31] Yu, D., Deng, L., 2016. Automatic Speech Recognition. Springer. [32] Zribi, I., Kammoun, I., Ellouze, M., Belguith, L., Blache, P., 2016. Sentence boundary detection for transcribed tunisian arabic, in: 13th Conference on Natural Language Processing (KONVENS 2016), pp. 323–331.  </biblio>
</article>
